Register of the National Republic records, 1918-1960
Hoover Institution Archives
- Communist Party Pamphlet File, 1920-1956 (Boxes 407-415)
  - Raushenbush, Winifred. "Jobs Without Creed or Color,", 1945
  - Raymond, Harry. "Dixie Comes to New York: Story of the Freeport GI Slayings,", 1946
  - Rochester, Anna and Pat Toohey. "The Miner's Road to Freedom,", 1935
  - Ross, Carl
    - "Let Freedom Ring for Earl Browder,", 1942
    - "Let's Pull together for Jobs, Security, Democracy and Peace,", 1938
  - Ross, M. "A History of Soviet Foreign Policy,", 1940
  - Ross, Stanley, "Communism in Latin America,", 1947
  - Ruthenberg, C. E. "The Workers (Communist) Party: What It Stands For, Why Workers Should Join,", undated
  - Ryhlick, Frank. "Congress and You,", 1943
  - Safarov, L. G. "Marx and the East,", 1934
  - Schneiderman, William. "The Pacific Coast Maritime Strike,", 1937
  - Semashko, N. A. "The Right to Rest and Leisure,", 1937
  - Shachtman, Max. "Ten Years: History and Principles of the Left Opposition,", 1933
  - Shaw, Ruth and H. A. Potamkin. "Our Lenin,", 1934
  - Shepilov, D. T. "Speech at the 20th Congress of the C.P.S.U.,", 1956
  - Sholokhov, Mikhail. "Hate,", 1942
  - Small, Sasha
    - "Ten Years of Labor Defense,", 1935
    - "Women in Action,", 1935
  - Smerkin, George and Sol Larks. "From Young Socialists to Young Communists,", 1934
  - Smith, Vern. "The Frame-Up System,", 1932
  - The Social Economic Foundation. "A Labor Party for the United States,", 1936
  - Soviet Russia Today (periodical). "The New Soviet Constitution,", 1936
  - Sparks, N. "The Struggle of the Marine Workers,", 1930
  - Spier, Leonard. "You Own the Hills,", 1935
  - Spiro, George. "Paris on the Barricades: A Story of the Commune of 1871,", 1929
  - Spivak, John L.
    - "Pattern for American Fascism,", 1947
    - "The 'Save the Country' Racket,", 1948
  - Stalin, Joseph
    - "Ein besseres Leben, ein frohes Legen!,", undated
    - "Foundations of Leninism,", 1934
    - "From Socialism to Communism in the Soviet Union,", 1939
    - "The Lenin Heritage,", 1934
    - "A Letter to Ivanov,", 1938
    - "Marxism vs. Liberalism: An Interview,", 1935
    - "The New Russian Policy (June 23, 1931),"
    - "Problems of Leninism,", 1934
    - "The Soviet Union and World Peace,", 1946
    - "Speed the Day of Victory,", 1943
    - "Stalin on the New Soviet Constitution,", 1936
    - "Stalin Speaks to the World,", 1941
    - "Stalin's Speeches on the American Communist Party,", 1929
    - "For Victory and Enduring Peace,", 1944
    - "Victory will be Ours!,", 1941
    - "Das wertsvollste Kapital - die Menschen,", 1935
  - Starobin, Joseph. "The Life and Death of an American Hero,", 1938
  - Stetsky, A. I. "Lenin on the Soviet State,", 1935
  - Stevens, Bennett. "The Church and the Workers,", 1932
  - Strong, Anna Louise
    - "Dictatorship and Democracy in the Soviet Union,", 1934
    - "Modern Farming - Soviet Style,", 1930
    - "The Soviet Union and World Peace,", 1935
  - Suslov, M. A. "Speech at the 20th Congress of the C.P.S.U.,", 1956
  - Taigin, I. "Here's How We See It, Mr. Perkins,", undated
  - Thompson, William O. "NRA from Within,", 1934
  - Thorez, Maurice. "The Unity of the French Nation,", 1936
  - Toohey, Pat. "NRA, Martial Law, 'Insurrection': The Miners Strike in New Mexico,", 1934
  - Trachtenberg, Alexander. "The History of May Day,", 1935
  - Trade Union Unity League. "Problems of Strike Strategy,", 1929
  - Trotsky, Leon. "The Kirov Assassination,", 1935
  - Uranov, S. "Espionage,", 1937 (Box 415)
  - Van Veen, Sadie. "Our Children Cry for Bread,", undated
  - Veritas. "Pro-War Communism,", 1937
  - Voroshilov, K. E.
    - "Ready for Defence!,", undated
    - "Stalin and the Red Army,", 1937
  - Ward, Harry F. "The Soviet Spirit,", undated
  - Wassiljew, B. "In der Illegalitaet: Aus dem Legen eines Berufsrevolutionaers,", 1934
  - Weinstone, William. "The Great Sit-Down Strike,", 1937
  - Weiss, Henry George. "Lenin Lives,", 1935
  - Weiss, Max
    - "Destroy Terrorism,", 1941
    - "Happy Days for American Youth,", 1935
    - "In Flanders Field Where Poppies Grow: The Truth about Decoration Day,", 1934
    - "What Price Profits?,", 1947
  - Wilkerson, Doxey A. "Why Negroes Are Joining the Communist Party,", 1946
  - Williams, Albert Rhys. "The Bolsheviks and the Communist Party,", 1946
  - Winston, Henry. "Old Jim Crow Has to Go!,", 1941
  - Wolfe, Bertram D.
    - "How Class Collaboration Works,", undated
    - "What is the Communist Opposition?,", undated
  - Yaroslavksy, E.
    - "The Meaning of the Soviet Trials,", 1938
    - "Religion in the U.S.S.R.,", 1934
  - Young Communist League
    - "Let's Fight Together!,", undated
    - "Stand Ready! The Call of the First International Children's Congress to All Proletarian Children,", 1929
  - Zetkin, Clara. "Lenin on the Women Question,", 1934
  - Zhdanov, A. A. "Organizational Problems of the Communist Party,", 1937
- Photo File (Boxes 785-814)
  Photographs, arranged alphabetically by subject. An index to photos used in National Republic can be found with the microfilmed material (boxes 815-817).
  - A-Ak (Box 785)
  - Adams
  - Al
  - Alams, The
  - Aliens - enemy
  - Allen
  - Am
  - America First Committee
  - American Federation of Labor
  - American Labor Party
  - American Youth Congress [2 folders]
  - An
  - Annapolis Naval Academy
  - Anti-Nazi, Anti-Communist
  - Ap-Aq
  - Ar
  - Argentina (Box 786)
  - Arlington Cemetery
  - Armour Research Foundation
  - Army
  - Art - paintings
  - As-Ay
  - Atheists
  - Atom bomb
  - Audubon, John James
  - Aviation, history of
  - Ba-Bal
  - Baldwin
  - Ban
  - Bands
  - Bara-Barm
  - Barn
  - Barr-Baru
  - Bax-Baz
  - Bea-Bei
  - Bel
  - Belgium
  - Ben
  - Benton, Thomas H.
  - Ber
  - Bi
  - Bl
  - Blaine, James G.
  - Bo-Bon
  - Bolivia
  - Boo-Boy
  - Boone, Daniel (Box 787)
  - Border Patrol
  - Boston
  - Boy Scouts
  - Bra
  - Brazil
  - Bre-Bri
  - Bridges of Washington D. C.
  - Bridges, Harry
  - Bridges Trial
  - Bro-Bry
  - Brooks
  - Brown
  - Bryant, William Cullen
  - Buc-Bul
  - Budenz, Louis F.
  - Bur
  - Burgoyne
  - Burr, Aaron
  - Bus
  - Butler
  - Butler, Senator Hugh
  - By
  - Cah-Cal
  - Calvert
  - Cam-Can
  - Canada
  - Car-Cav
  - Carasso, Dr. Alexander H.
  - Carroll, Charles of Carrollton, Maryland
  - Cartoons (Box 788)
  - Ce
  - Censuring
  - Central and South America
  - Cha
  - Chaplains
  - Chase
  - Che-Cho
  - Chile
  - China
  - Christmas
  - Christoffel, Harold
  - Churches
  - Ci
  - CIO
    - General
    - Miscellaneous
    - Leaders
    - Men
  - Cl (Box 789)
  - Clark
  - Clay, Henry
  - Coa-Coh
  - Coe, V. Frank
  - Col-Com
  - Colombia
  - Colonial
  - Columbians
  - Columbus, Christopher
  - Committees - commissions - conferences - miscellaneous
  - Communist conspiracy trials
    - Trial of 11
    - Trial of 9
  - Communist Party
    - Headquarters
    - Leaders, Includes "second string" communists
    - Leaders (Box 790)
  - Communists (men)
    - Ba
    - Be
    - Bi-Bl-Bo
    - Br-Bu
    - Browder
    - C
    - D
    - E-F
    - Eisler, Gerhart
    - Eisler, Hans
    - Foster, William Z.
    - Ga-Ge
    - Gi-Go-Gr-Gu
    - J
    - Ma
    - Mc-Mo
    - Mi
    - P
    - R-S
    - Wa-We-Wh
    - Wi-Wo
  - Con
  - Conference
  - Congress (Box 791)
    - General
    - Senators and Representatives
  - Conscientious objectors
  - Consolidated Engineering Corporation
  - Constitution
  - Coo-Cox
  - Coolidge, Calvin
  - Cornwallis
  - Cr
  - Criminals
  - Crockett, David
  - Cu-Cz
  - Cuba
  - Custer, General George A.
  - Da
  - Daily Worker (periodical)
  - Davis
  - Dawes, Charles E.
  - Dea-Dem
  - Declaration of Independence
  - Demonstrations
    - Chicago
    - Michigan - Ohio
    - Mosinee, Wisconsin
    - New Jersey
    - New York [2 folders]
    - New York [2 folders] (Box 792)
    - Philadelphia
    - Pittsburgh - Philadelphia
    - Washington, D.C.
    - Miscellaneous cities
    - Against Mundt - Nixon Bill
    - American - Soviet friendship
    - Concerning Spain
    - Eleven Communists
    - Unidentifiable
    - Miscellaneous
  - Den
  - Dep-Dew
  - Dewey, Thomas E.
  - Di
  - Dies Committee - witnesses
  - Dies, Martin (Box 793)
  - Do
  - Douglas, Stephen A.
  - Dr.
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - Ea-Ed
  - Eg-El
  - Eisenhower, D. D.
  - Elections - voting
  - Ellis
  - Em-Er
  - Emspak, Julius
  - England
  - Es-Ew
  - Espionage
    - Atomic
    - Canada
    - Japanese
    - Nazi
    - Sedition (Box 794)
    - U.S. Government - Hiss, Chambers, Coplon, et al.
    - Miscellaneous
  - Fa-Fe
  - Fascism
  - F.B.I
  - Federal Hall
  - Fi
  - Field
  - Fl
  - Flag
  - Fo
  - Food
  - Ford
  - Foreign agents
  - Forts
  - Fra (Box 795)
  - France
  - Franklin, Benjamin
  - Fre
  - Fremont
  - Fri-Fru
  - Fu
  - Ga-Gal
  - Gan-Gav
  - Garfield, James A.
  - Ge
  - Germany
  - Gh-Gi
  - Gilbert
  - Gl
  - Go
  - Government officials - U.S.
  - Gra (Box 796)
  - Grant, Ulysses S.
  - Gre
  - Green
  - Gri-Gru
  - Gu-Gw
  - Guatemala
  - Hab-Hal
  - Hale
  - Hall
  - Halleck
  - Ham
  - Hamilton, Alexander
  - Han-Hap
  - Hancock, John
  - Handicapped
  - Har
  - Harding, Warren G.
  - Harper's Ferry
  - Harrison, Benjamin
  - Harrison, William Henry
  - Hart
  - Has-Hat
  - Hau-Haw
  - Hawaii [2 folders]
  - Hay
  - Hayes, Rutherford B.
  - Hea-Hen
  - Henry, Patrick
  - Her-Hew
  - Hi-Hl
  - Hickey
  - Highways
  - Hiss
  - Hob-Hog
  - Hol
  - Hoo-Hop
  - Hoover (Box 797)
  - Hos-Hou
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities
    - General
    - Witnesses
  - House committees - miscellaneous
  - How
  - Hub-Hum
  - Hughes
  - Hun-Hux
  - Hy
  - I
  - Independence Hall
  - Indians
  - Investigating committees
    - California
    - House
    - New York - Texas - Illinois - Washington, D.C.
    - Senate
    - Washington State
  - Italy
  - Ja
  - Jackson, Andrew
  - Jamestown, Va.
  - Japan
  - Japanese - Chinese boycott (Box 798)
  - Je-Ji
  - Jefferson, Thomas
  - Jenner, Senator William E.
  - Jo-Ju
  - Johnson
  - Jones
  - Ka
  - Ke
  - Ken
  - Kennedy
  - Ki
  - Kl-Kn
  - Ko
  - Kr
  - Ku
  - Ku Klux Klan
  - Lad-Lam
  - Lafayette
  - Lan
  - Lap-Law
  - Lawson, John Howard
  - Le
  - Lee
  - Lev
  - Lewis, John L.
  - Li
  - Lightfoot, Claude Mark
  - Lighthouses
  - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 799)
  - Lo-Lom
  - Logan, John A.
  - Lon-Lou
  - Longfellow
  - Lu-Ly
  - Ma-Mal
  - MacArthur
  - McC
  - McCarran, Pat
  - McCarthy, Joe
  - McD
  - McF-McK
  - McKinley, William
  - McM-McN
  - McNamara, William M
  - Madison, James
  - Man-May
  - Maps
  - Mar
  - Marines
  - Marshall, John (Box 800)
  - Martin
  - Mason
  - Matthews, J. B.
  - Matusow, Harvey
  - Me
  - Mexico
  - Mi
  - Mifflin, Thomas
  - Miller
  - Mills
  - Mo
  - Mon
  - Monroe, James
  - Monuments and statues
  - Mor
  - Morris
  - Morse, Samuel
  - Morton
  - Moses, George H.
  - Movies (Box 801)
  - Mu
  - Muhlenberg
  - Mundt, Senator Karl E.
  - Museum (National) - Washington D. C.
  - Mystic Seaport, Mystic, Connecticut
  - Na
  - National Labor Relations Board
  - National Republic
    - Cuts
    - Original heading
  - Nazism - United States
  - Ne
  - Negroes
  - Nelson, Steve
  - New Mexico
  - New Orleans
  - Ni
  - Nixon, Richard M.
  - No-Ny (Box 802)
  - Ob-Od
  - Oceola
  - Og-Ol
  - Om-Ox
  - Pac-Pai
  - Pacifists
  - Pal-Pas
  - Pap-Pau
  - Pat
  - Patriotic
  - Pea-Pen
  - Pep-Pet
  - Pershing, John J.
  - Ph
  - Philippine Islands
  - Pi
  - Pickets
  - Pierce, Franklin (Box 803)
  - Pioneers
  - Pl
  - Po-Pop
  - Poe, Edgar Allan
  - Poland
  - Polk, James K.
  - Ponger, Kurt L.
  - Ports and harbor
  - Pos-Pu
  - Postal Service and Post Office buildings
  - Pr
  - Projects
  - Puerto Rico
  - Q
  - Ra
  - Railroads and locomotives
  - Randolph
  - Re
  - Read
  - Reed
  - Religious
  - Remington, William E. and Ann
  - Revere, Paul
  - Reynolds
  - Ri
  - Rivera, Diego (Mexico)
  - Ro-Roo
  - Robeson, Paul and Peekskill, New York
  - Roosevelt
  - Ros-Row (Box 804)
  - Rosenberg, Ethel and Julius
  - Rothschild
  - Ru
  - Russia
  - Sa-Sal
  - Sabotage
  - San-Sav
  - Santa Fe, N. M.
  - Sc-Se
  - Scenic
  - Sch
  - Senate Internal Security Subcommittee
  - Senate Investigating Subcommittee
  - Senate Judiciary Subcommittee
  - Sha (Box 805)
  - She
  - Sherman, William T.
  - Sherwood
  - Ships (famous)
  - Sho
  - Si-Sl
  - Sm-So
  - Smith
  - Smithsonian Institution
  - Socialists
  - Society of the Cincinnati
  - Sp
  - Spain
  - Sports
  - Sta
  - State capitals
  - Statue of Liberty
  - Ste-Sti
  - Stevens
  - Sto
  - Str
  - Strikes
    - California
    - Illinois - Wisconsin
    - Michigan
  - Strikes (Box 806)
    - New Jersey
    - New York
    - Ohio - Minnesota
    - Pennsylvania
    - Washington D. C.
    - Miscellaneous
  - Students - American Student Union
  - Su-Sy-Sw
  - Sullivan
  - Sutter
  - Switzerland
  - Ta
  - Taft
  - Taylor
  - Te
  - Teachers, Coudert-Rapp Committee
  - Th
  - Thanksgiving
  - Thomas
  - Ti
  - To
  - Tr
  - Treason
  - Trees (famous)
  - Truman, Harry S.
  - Tu-Ty
  - U (Box 807)
  - United Nations
  - Unknown soldier
  - Va
  - Valley Forge
  - Van Buren, Martin
  - Ve
  - Venezuela
  - Veterans
  - Vi-Vo
  - Virginia, University of
  - Voice of America
  - Von Steuben, Baron
  - Wa-Wal
  - Wallace, Henry and Wallace-for-President Movement
  - War-Way
  - War - miscellaneous
  - Warren
  - Washington D. C.
    - Botanical Gardens
    - Buildings
      - A - B - C - D - E
      - American Red Cross
      - Constitution Hall
      - D.A.R. Hall
      - F - G - H - I - J
      - Folger Shakespeare Library
      - Freer Art Gallery
      - K - L - M - N - O
      - National Art Gallery
      - P - Q - R - S - T
      - U - V - W - X - Y - Z
      - Union Station
    - Government buildings (Box 808)
      - A - B - C - D - E
      - Archives
      - Capitol
      - Court houses
      - Department of Justice
      - F - G - H - I - J
      - Federal Reserve
      - Government Printing Office
      - "Government Triangle"
      - Interior
      - K - L - M - N - O
      - Library of Congress
      - P - Q - R - S - T
      - Pan American
      - Patent Office
      - Post Office buildings
      - State Department
      - Supreme Court
      - Treasury
      - U.S. Chamber of Commerce
      - War Department
      - Weather Bureau
      - Unidentified
    - Georgetown
    - History
    - The Mall
    - Maps - plans
    - Pennsylvania Avenue
    - White House
      - Exterior
      - Interior
    - Zoo
    - Miscellaneous
  - Washington, George (Box 809)
  - Web-Wei
  - Webster, Daniel
  - Wel-Wey
  - West Point
  - Western Union
  - Wh
  - Whitney, Eli
  - Wi-Wil
  - Will
  - Williamsburg, Virginia
  - Wilson
  - Win-Wit
  - Wo
  - Women
  - Women (Box 810)
  - Workers Alliance
  - W.P.A.
  - Wr-Wy
  - X-Y
  - York, Pennsylvania
  - Young Communists
  - Z
  - Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous (Box 811-814)
- Sound Recordings (Record cabinet)
  Four 10" lacquer sound discs.
- Oversize Material, 1918-1919 (Box 992)
  - Album of World War I political cartoons, 1918 April - 1919 April (Box 992)
- Addendum: Card Files, 1919-1959 (Boxes 824-991)
  The addendum to the National Republic records consists of index card files maintained by the National Republic staff up until 1960. A single Individual Name Index File, comprising 163 card file boxes, is central.
  No statement of criteria for inclusion in the file is available, but internal evidence suggests that it is a file of individuals whom the anti-communist journal considered politically objectionable. They include: Communist Party, USA leaders; writers for the Communist Party press; persons mentioned favorably in Communist Party press articles; persons cited in Congressional and state legislative anti-communist reports; officers and sponsors of organizations cited as or alleged to be Communist Party fronts or to be infiltrated by the Communist Party; persons publicly defending the legal rights of alleged communists and/or objecting to anti-communist legislative investigations; signers of petitions to put Communist Party candidates on the ballot in 1940; subscribers to Communist Party press publications in 1942; leaders of other socialist parties or organizations; and public advocates of left-wing causes or policies, including racial integration, immigration, and internationalist and peace policies.
  The range of associations triggering an index card is considerable and includes affiliation with a number of liberal, labor and religious organizations that have often not been considered to be within the Communist Party orbit. Among these are the American Civil Liberties Union, Americans for Democratic Action, the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, and at least one self-proclaimed anti-communist organization, the American Committee for Cultural Freedom. A number of individuals who held high political office (among them former, sitting, and future presidents of the United States) are indexed. The card file constitutes a veritable Who's Who of American communism and of those caught up in the Cold War communist controversy.
  Cards cite sources in which the individual's name appears. Most often these are articles in the Communist Party press, but they also include the sources suggested by the categories enumerated above.
  - Individual name card file, 1919-1959 (Box 824-986)
    Index card file of names of individuals, referenced to sources in which the names appear. Arranged alphabetically.
    - A - Ag (Box 824)
    - Ah - Allen, I (Box 825)
    - Allen, J - Anderson, G (Box 826)
    - Anderson, H - Ari (Box 827)
    - Ark - Aw (Box 828)
    - Ax - Baldwin, M (Box 829)
    - Baldwin, R - Barn (Box 830)
    - Baro - Baum (Box 831)
    - Bauma - Belk (Box 832)
    - Bell - Berger (Box 833)
    - Bergerm - Bet (Box 834)
    - Beu - Black, I (Box 835)
    - Black, J - Blum (Box 836)
    - Blumb - Born (Box 837)
    - Boro - Bradw (Box 838)
    - Brady - Brigg (Box 839)
    - Brigh - Brown, B (Box 840)
    - Brown, C - Bryan (Box 841)
    - Bryans - Burl (Box 842)
    - Burm - Cadd (Box 843)
    - Cade - Cao (Box 844)
    - Cap - Carr (Box 845)
    - Cars - Chal (Box 846)
    - Cham - Che (Box 847)
    - Chi - Clark, R (Box 848)
    - Clark, S - Cohen, I (Box 849)
    - Cohen, J - Colon (Box 850)
    - Coloni - Cooper, P (Box 851)
    - Cooper, R - Coz (Box 852)
    - Cr - Cro (Box 853)
    - Cru - Danielo (Box 854)
    - Daniels - Davis, D (Box 855)
    - Davis, E - Dec (Box 856)
    - Ded - Derl (Box 857)
    - Derm - Dip (Box 858)
    - Dir - Dor (Box 859)
    - Dos - DuBoi (Box 860)
    - Dubov - Eam (Box 861)
    - Ear - Ei (Box 862)
    - Ek - Enge (Box 863)
    - Engl - Ewe (Box 864)
    - Ewi - Feine (Box 865)
    - Feing - Find (Box 866)
    - Fine - Flat (Box 867)
    - Flau - Ford, J (Box 868)
    - Ford, L - France (Box 869)
    - Frances - Friedl (Box 870)
    - Friedm - Gaine (Box 871)
    - Gaino - Garrig (Box 872)
    - Garris - Gerk (Box 873)
    - Gerl - Gim (Box 874)
    - Gin - Goldberg, C (Box 875)
    - Goldberg, D - Goodc (Box 876)
    - Goode - Got (Box 877)
    - Gou - Green, A (Box 878)
    - Green, B - Griffin (Box 879)
    - Griffit - Gur (Box 880)
    - Gus - Hallg (Box 881)
    - Halli - Hap (Box 882)
    - Har - Harris, R (Box 883)
    - Harris, S - Hav (Box 884)
    - Haw - Hein (Box 885)
    - Heis - Herna (Box 886)
    - Hernd - Hil (Box 887)
    - Him - Hollid (Box 888)
    - Hollin - House (Box 889)
    - Housk - Humphrey, H (Box 890)
    - Humphrey, J - Ingl (Box 891)
    - Ingr - Jack (Box 892)
    - Jaco - Jenne (Box 893)
    - Jenni - Johnson, I (Box 894)
    - Johnson, J - Jones, I (Box 895)
    - Jones, J - Kahn, A (Box 896)
    - Kahn, B - Kar (Box 897)
    - Kas - Kellen (Box 898)
    - Keller - Ker (Box 899)
    - Kes - Kirke (Box 900)
    - Kirkl - Koce (Box 901)
    - Koch - Kram (Box 902)
    - Kran - Kushne (Box 903)
    - Kushni - Lande (Box 904)
    - Landf - Lauf (Box 905)
    - Laug - Lee (Box 906)
    - Leeb - Let (Box 907)
    - Leu - Lewis, J (Box 908)
    - Lewis, K - Linf (Box 909)
    - Ling - Lom (Box 910)
    - Lon - Lub (Box 911)
    - Luc - MacC (Box 912)
    - MacD - Mak (Box 913)
    - Mal - Marcl (Box 914)
    - Marco - Marte (Box 915)
    - Marth - Mati (Box 916)
    - Matl - McA (Box 917)
    - McB - McGim (Box 918)
    - McGin - McO (Box 919)
    - McP - Meo (Box 920)
    - Mer - Milk (Box 921)
    - Mill - Mind (Box 922)
    - Mine - Mono (Box 923)
    - Monr - Mork (Box 924)
    - Morl - Mot (Box 925)
    - Mou - Murra (Box 926)
    - Murre - Neh (Box 927)
    - Nei - News (Box 928)
    - Newt - North (Box 929)
    - Northc - Oden (Box 930)
    - Odet - Orm (Box 931)
    - Orn - Pall (Box 932)
    - Palm - Pash (Box 933)
    - Pask - Pearm (Box 934)
    - Pears - Perry, K (Box 935)
    - Perry, L - Phillips, K (Box 936)
    - Phillips, L - Platt, D (Box 937)
    - Platt, E - Pos (Box 938)
    - Pot - Pri (Box 939)
    - Pro - Rame (Box 940)
    - Rami - Redd (Box 941)
    - Rede - Rer (Box 942)
    - Res - Richardson, C (Box 943)
    - Richardson, D - Robb (Box 944)
    - Robe - Robinson, H (Box 945)
    - Robinson, I - Ron (Box 946)
    - Roo - Roso (Box 947)
    - Ross - Rubinstein, C (Box 948)
    - Rubinstein, D - Sachm (Box 949)
    - Sachs - Sanf (Box 950)
    - Sang - Schap (Box 951)
    - Schar - Schneider (Box 952)
    - Schneiderm - Scott, G (Box 953)
    - Scott, H - Sel (Box 954)
    - Sem - Shaw, D (Box 955)
    - Shaw, E - Ship (Box 956)
    - Shir - Silo (Box 957)
    - Sils - Sj (Box 958)
    - Sk - Smith, F (Box 959)
    - Smith, G - Sobe (Box 960)
    - Sobi - Spencer, S (Box 961)
    - Spencer, T - Starn (Box 962)
    - Staro - Step (Box 963)
    - Ster - Stone, D (Box 964)
    - Stone, E - Strong, A (Box 965)
    - Strong, B - Swa (Box 966)
    - Swe - Tau (Box 967)
    - Tav - Thei (Box 968)
    - Thel - Thorm (Box 969)
    - Thorn - Tooh (Box 970)
    - Tool - Tuch (Box 971)
    - Tuck - Uret (Box 972)
    - Urey - Vick (Box 973)
    - Vict - Walken (Box 974)
    - Walker - Ward, P (Box 975)
    - Ward, R - Way (Box 976)
    - We - Weisk (Box 977)
    - Weisl - West, H (Box 978)
    - West, J - White (Box 979)
    - Whitef - William (Box 980)
    - Williams - Willn (Box 981)
    - Willo - Wip (Box 982)
    - Wir - Won (Box 983)
    - Woo - Yak (Box 984)
    - Yal - Zak (Box 985)
    - Zal - Zy (Box 986)
  - Miscellaneous card files, circa 1950-1960 (Box 987-991)
    - Miscellaneous individual name cards (Box 987)
      Includes unfiled, unfinished, duplicate, and 1960 cards. Unsorted.
    - Communist Party, U.S.A. leaders as of 1960 (Box 988)
      Individual name cards referenced by Communist Party press articles reporting recent activities. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Miscellaneous organization name and topical cards referenced by Communist Party press and other journal articles (Box 989)
      Arranged alphabetically.
    - Miscellaneous individual and organization name and topical cards referenced by National Republic articles (Box 990)
      Very incomplete. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Miscellaneous individual and organization name and topical cards referenced by obsolete Hazel Hoffman office file numbers (Box 991)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1942, 1945 (Box 37)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfield records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2015 December release of records, 1942, 1945 (Box 37)
    Consists of a newspaper clipping from the San Francisco Chronicle, 17 October 1942, "From Where I Sit: The True Tale of a Lady Who Leaves Her Hotel Suite Each Day to Be a Welder," and abstracts of post-war literature produced by the Library of Conference Legislative Reference Service, May 1945.